<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Work - Category - GaiusRed</title><link>https://gaius.red/categories/work/</link><description>Work - Category - GaiusRed</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>erik@gaius.red (Erik Gaius Capistrano)</managingEditor><webMaster>erik@gaius.red (Erik Gaius Capistrano)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 23:59:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaius.red/categories/work/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>14 Strategies for Objectivity in Software Development</title><link>https://gaius.red/crafting-code-not-egos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 23:59:59 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/crafting-code-not-egos/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/gaiusred_IKEA_in_Cyberspace_18ffacf2-381a-4992-af12-8e7d08323562.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>My latest article, Crafting Code, Not Egos: 14 Strategies for Objectivity in Software Development delves into the IKEA effect and its influence on our emotional attachment to code. It offers practical advice on maintaining objectivity, embracing constructive criticism, and fostering a collaborative environment. Whether you're a seasoned developer or new to the field, these strategies can help you navigate the emotional aspects of coding and contribute to more resilient and adaptable software solutions. Read the full article and join the conversation by sharing your experiences with overcoming attachment in software development.</description></item><item><title>A Product Owner's Guide to Creating Effective User Stories</title><link>https://gaius.red/slicing-the-agile-cake/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 23:59:59 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/slicing-the-agile-cake/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/jo-szczepanska-5aiRb5f464A-unsplash.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Excited to share my latest article on the art of breaking down work into user stories in Agile projects. Learn practical strategies for creating effective, manageable units of work that align with end-user needs. Check it out and let me know your thoughts!</description></item><item><title>Enhancing Efficiency with ChatGPT</title><link>https://gaius.red/prompts-and-productivity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 23:59:59 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/prompts-and-productivity/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/gaiusred_a_japanese_salaryman_and_a_sleek_robot_shaking_hands_w_b1cb4238-c9e1-48c2-8a98-6fc8893b1049.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Ever wondered how Artificial Intelligence could elevate your productivity as a Product Owner? Check out seven of my most used prompts in my latest article 'Prompts & Productivity: Enhancing Efficiency with ChatGPT'. Unleash new levels of efficiency and redefine your workflow today!]]></description></item><item><title>Rethinking Restrictions on AI Tools in the Workplace</title><link>https://gaius.red/innovation-at-risk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 19:34:01 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/innovation-at-risk/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/innovation-at-risk.gif" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Change is often met with resistance, especially when it comes to new technology in the workplace. But what if our apprehensions are holding back the potential for innovation? In my latest article, I delve into the debate surrounding the use of AI tools, advocating for a balanced approach that promotes progress while addressing security concerns. Join me in this exploration and let's open up the conversation about the future of work.</description></item><item><title>The Role of Databases in Modern Models</title><link>https://gaius.red/expanding-ai-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 19:34:01 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/expanding-ai-capabilities/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/expanding-ai-capabilities-1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>In the evolving landscape of AI, it's crucial to explore fresh approaches that can boost efficiency and adaptability. My latest article dives into one such fascinating concept – integrating databases directly with AI models. It's a nuanced shift that carries significant potential. If you're curious about the future of AI and how we can optimize it, you might find this read enlightening. Check it out here and let's start a conversation!</description></item><item><title>A Tale of Trust, Verification, and Intellectual Humility</title><link>https://gaius.red/navigating-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 19:34:01 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/navigating-change/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/navigating-change-1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>How do you balance trust and verification in the dynamic world of Agile IT? I share my personal experiences and lessons learned in my journey from Engineering to Product Management in my latest article. Check it out!</description></item><item><title>Agile Methods Every Product Owner Should Know</title><link>https://gaius.red/the-art-of-prioritization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 19:34:01 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/the-art-of-prioritization/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/the-art-of-prioritization-1.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Hey everyone! Just dropped a fresh article on agile prioritization methods. Perfect for Product Owners/Managers looking for a quick overview. Curious? Give it a read!</description></item><item><title>Surviving the Stakeholder Safari: A Product Owner's Guide</title><link>https://gaius.red/surviving-the-stakeholder-safari/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 19:34:01 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/surviving-the-stakeholder-safari/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/surviving-the-stakeholder-safari-1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Excited to share my thoughts on an intriguing approach to stakeholder management in agile environments. I delve into how understanding different stakeholder 'profiles' can enhance our communication and lead to improved project outcomes.</description></item><item><title>Reevaluating AI Understanding in the Age of LLMs</title><link>https://gaius.red/going-thru-the-chinese-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 19:34:01 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/going-thru-the-chinese-room/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/going-thru-the-chinese-room-1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Can modern AI escape from Searle's Chinese Room? I did not expect to dive this deep because of a random TikTok vid...</description></item><item><title>A Generational Shift in Solving Issues</title><link>https://gaius.red/generational-shift-in-solving-issues/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 23:41:01 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://gaius.red/generational-shift-in-solving-issues/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/generational-shift-in-solving-issues-1.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Younger millennials' problem-solving methods differ from what we are used to. In order to properly assist them in dealing with these issues, we must also change our approach.</description></item></channel></rss>